synced by Zirkhaki
If yet your blood does not rage..
..then it is water that flows in your veins.
For what is the flush of youth..
..if it is not of service to the motherland.
Just a minute Mr. McKinley, one revolutionary is meeting another.
Thank you. Shall we go?
I'm sorry it had to end this way.
This isn't the end Mr. McKinley. This is just the beginning.
There will be others after we have gone. Many others.
I always believed that there were two kinds of men in this world.
Men who go to their death screaming and men..
..who go to their death in silence.
And then I met the third kind.
Sometimes in my dreams I can still see them making their..
..long last walk.
They never so much as broke their stride.
They never faltered.
But above all others I remembered his eyes.
How they looked at me. Clear, defiant..
..never wavering.
It's time..
Hi.. - Hi..
Good morning..
Good morning. - Good morning.
So, Sonia, my contact in Delhi, has gathered some information..
..and we have to wire her some money to secure it.
Everything is cash up there.
Have I come to the wrong meeting?
We had directive from above, by Jacobs.
We had to make some very tough decisions.
Sorry Sue, I am really sorry.
If you do an episode on Gandhi that would work for us..
You know Gandhi sells, I suggest some fairy tales or even Robin Hood.
But these revolutionaries, Bhagat Singh, Chandrashekhar Ali..
It's Azad, Chandrashekhar Azad and Azad means freedom.
Azad sorry and I know what it means Sue.
I don't believe this, everything has been set up..
..and I have been working on this for the past two years.
I have been going to Hindi night classes.
Look..- Please, their story deserves to be told.
This is my grandfather's diary. He was an eye witness.
This is filled with real conversations.
Their very words. Boys not older than 23 fighting the empire.
That's an important story. A bloody important..
This is not the end Miss McKinley.
Sue.. Sue.
Can I talk to you?
Where are you going? - To India, to shoot a documentary.
I'll send you a postcard. - How? With what?
Your Mother's eye.
Are you talking or hijacking her?
Get out of the way! Scoot!
First time in India, madam? Don't worry. - Yes! No..
Are you married? Even I and my wife are married.
Sue, you don't have to worry he is with me.
Yeah, I am with her.. With me.
Oh, it's so good to see you.
I can't believe it you are here. That it's happening at last.
Sorry about the short notice.
Mind-blowing! Your Hindi has really improved. - Thank you.
Don't worry, all the preparations are done.
Hey Sue, no need to worry..
All the preparations are done.
..posters have been put up everywhere.
It's also been announced on radio.
just see, they'll be lining up for the auditions.
What's wrong?
I didn't tell you. The truth is that I've come alone.
..no money, no producer is going to arrive.
I know. - You knew it!
After Alice, there was a call from Beth Williams..
..she informed me of the cancellation of the show..
..and also my services.
By the way, did you abuse her in Hindi?
She wanted to know what it meant.
I explained to her in graphic detail.
You are amazing.. Sonia.
What's that? - That's the Red Fort.
This is Delhi University. Let me help you with your luggage.
How much? - Ma'am I've already told you.
No, no.. - I can help.
Thanks Ravi, you are a sweetheart.
Ravi, please get all the luggage to our room. - Fine.
Thank you.
Hello which country, madam? - India, I hope.
Your room. - Okay.
Get some rest now. I'll see you tomorrow..
..If you need anything you have my number.
Thanks. - Okay.
Let's go Ravi.
My Grandpa was right..
..he said when you come to India, it's love at first sight.
Hi this is Dabbo speaking. And my hobbies..
..are bikes, babes and body building.
"Little child what do you behold in your infant hands.."
Oh no!
I can't do this.
Listen.. - Just try once.
I deserve a role because I have dimples just like Priety Zinta.
"When flowers in the garden bloom.."
"Jana, Gana, Mana, Vande Matram.."
Because women can make possible impossible..
..impossible possible.
I love you.
Hi, how's that?
"When flowers in the garden bloom.."
Don't sing. Just recite "Vande Matram". - Vande Matram?
"Vande Matram Jana, Gana, Mana.." "Vande Matram Jana, Gana, Mana.."
Rascal, if you have the guts then come out.
Everyone calls me Bhai..
Raise your hand and say Vande Matram! - Vande Matram!
Speak loudly, Vande Matram! - Vande Matram.
Loudly and proudly, Vande Matram! - Vande Matram
Vande Matram! - Vande Matram..
I know about the fight.
I have dedicated my life to the freedom of this nation.
I know you want me to get married.
..but Freedom is my bride.
I know.. I know.. that..
I know.. that you want me to get married..
..but my bride is Freedom
..but my bride is Freedom.
Your obedient son, Bhagat Singh.
Bhagat Singh.
Bhagat Singh. - Anybody.
My turn. - My turn.
My name is Bhagat Singh. Inquilab Zindabad.
Tea! - Thanks.
Depressed huh?
One or two of them can be used for minor roles..
..but no one's even close for Azad or Bhagat Singh.
I guess it's all my fault.
No Sonia. You're my rock. It's my fault. I should have never come.
Sue, don't get so dejected.
I think we need a break.
Let's go and have some fun. - I'm in no mood Sonia.
We are going to the classroom. - Classroom.
Lose control.
One more chance, Lose.. lose..
C'mon..
Lose control.
Mr. Poet.. - Hey Sonia.
What's happening?
How are you? - Fine. How are you?
Aslam.. Sue McKinley. - Hi.
You too study at the University?
Wow! Her Hindi is great.
We live there, eat there..
..but no one has ever accused us of studying there.
What do you say Sonia? - Come.
DJ! DJ! DJ!..
Who are those maniacs?
That's DJ..
DJ I love you!!!
That's Sukhi.
Let's rock it!
DJ I love you!!!
I love you too baby!
Hey, bring it. .
DJ! DJ! DJ!..
- What are you doing?
Damn exhibitionists.
They'll never change.
Come on dude, let's rock it! - Let's do it.
Come on, Sukhi. Show everyone.
DJ! DJ! DJ!..
Is he OK?
That's his natural pose.
Hey, pal. - DJ.
Sukhi, all parts working? - DJ!
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa! Who is this?
Sue this is DJ. DJ this is Sue. - Hi!
Sue? She's so pink her name should be Gulabo (Rose). - DJ.
She's quite hot..
I mean it's very cold.
Karan you saved my life. I love you! - Love you too, Sukhi.
Aslam..
..you too saved my life,
I love you too!
It's ok.
She must have saved my life too..
No! Sukhi! She didn't save your life.
No problem. One day she'll save my life.
Coming.. - Hey brother, take a hike. She is your sister-in-law.
"One more time.." "Lose Control.."
"Lose Control."
"I'm a Rebel.."
"I am a rebel."
"There's aren't any students here, no teachers to suffer.."
"Our school is a school filled with fun."
"Lose Control.."
Sukhi you just sit and watch like a dumb-ass..
DJ doesn't waste a second.
He's a stud.
Hi! How's everybody? Hi Rahul! What's up?
Got a few gigs lined up.
How's your radio thing going?
Its not Radio thing, it is Radio Jockey.
Did anything work out?
All India Radio has given me a night slot.
Means your scene is shaping up!
Not really. When the whole world's sleeping I'm on air.
But people stay up late..
Criminals, insomniacs, watchmen and idiots!
Have your fun at my expense.
Speaking of expenses.. Can I..
Trial Job, No income.
Thanks man, thanks a lot.
See you guys. Got a cigarette?
Okay, see you. Take care, thanks.
Fabulous! - Leave it.
It's my Dad's money. He's got loads of it..
Stop this Western music, this obscenity!
How many times do I have to make you understand this!
Polluting the culture of this country..
Leave this place right now. Leave!
Can't you understand, bastard!
This is your last warning..
..from now on, nobody plays any Western music out here.
No lewd dancing!
It is better you listen or I'll break your legs.
Who are you to warn us? If you don't like it, don't come here.
You bloody Pakistani!
Let's finish it.
Hey, empty this place.
Last warning! Got it?
Long live India!
Get up. Empty this place or we will arrest you.
You touch Aslam and see what I do to you..
..even your mother won't recognize you.
Ever seen a baboons arse?
Yours will be as red after I've finished with you.
Sir, I'm sure we can work it out. Come here. No matter..
You think too much of yourself don't you?
Keep this..
Was that a bribe?
Welcome to India Sue!
Anyone hungry? I'm famished.
Hey Sue, want a ride?
You've got insurance?
Karan..
Love you..
Shit!
Almost, almost..
You..!
How're you?
Hey honey! Come here you..
If something happened to you, I'd have killed you.
Is this any way to greet your boyfriend?
How're you?
Hey, how are you? - I am fine, how are you?
Mr. Rathod.. - Aslam, you keep growing tall.
Stop acting..
Sexy jacket, bro. - It is.
Hi, Ajay.. - Hi.
Flight lieutenant Ajay Rathod. - She's right.
Hurry guys, I'm famished.
You won't get any food here.
Hey Mitro, my mother, how are you? - Your Mitro is dead.
Stay away! You remembered your mother after two months..
..I carried you in my stomach for nine months..
..and washed your bum for years..
..and you come here as being a gentleman.
Get lost!
Does anyone bother to check if Mitro is alive or dead?
What's up?
You're drunk again.
No. No. No. - One is in military and other keeps enjoying.
First give us food ma, and then yell at us all night.
None of you have eaten? What will happen to this generation?
Sonia you've lost even more weight. - Really.. Mitro
The girls of today have more bones and less flesh..
How will you bear children?
Aslam, how are you my son? I didn't notice you.
He is my true son who bothers to check on me.
And he is one.. I committed a mistake by sending you to city.
Look ma, what I brought for you.
Your daughter-in-law. Her name is Sue.
What? A foreigner?
Brought her especially from London.
That's why I was away for so long.
I told her that's it's your first trip to India.
Give me your blessings Ma.
Your son's such a brat.
God! She understands Hindi!
She understands everything.
You really understand everything? - Yes.
What a problem!
I'm going off to sleep. Your beds are all ready.
No need to drive so late at night.
I saw them then..
..like they leapt out of the pages of grandpa's dairy.
Bhagat Singh, Chandrashekhar Azad, Rajguru ..
..and Durga Bhabhi, Asfaqulla Khan
And they were sitting right in front of me.
Sue, where are you?
Will you guys act in my film?
What?
Will you guys act in my film? You all are perfect.
Hey, why are you guys laughing? I'm the hero of her film.
Yeah we guys are champions when it comes to acting..
..clowning around is all they do.
I am serious okay.
The four of you will be perfect for the roles of Bhagat Singh..
..Chandrashekar Azad, Ashfaqulla Khan, Rajguru.
And Sonia will be my Durga Bhabhi.
She really knows Hindi!
All this talk of patriotism is boring.
Boring? These guys gave their lives for the freedom of your country.
What freedom? Have you seen the state of this country?
No one believes this rubbish thing.
Excuse me! I believe in this country, Karan.
Otherwise, why would I be fighting for it? - I don't know.
Maybe because it's cool! Being a pilot.. flying an expensive plane.
You get to wear fancy jackets..
And the women.. women love men in uniforms.
Sure I love being a pilot. Sure it's cool.
But I also feel proud of my country, and I can give my life for it.
Proud of what?
..this country's exploding population?
..or unemployment.. - or corruption?
Which of these are you really proud of?
Come on guys..
..no country's perfect Karan. We've got to make it better.
Right.
Ok, Ajay you make this country perfect.
The minute I get my degree I'm out of this dump..
You won't be able to leave us and go. - Wait and see.
She speaks Hindi so well!
Why didn't you tell me you son of a bitch..
..I was making a fool of myself.
At least ask them once, please.
So you won't give up.
Ok. But nobody will turn up.
They will come. I'll get them. That's a promise.
Karan put your cigarette out.
Greetings grandpa!
God bless you. When did you come?
Just last night. Some friends.
Who is he? - DJ's grandfather.
Bye. - Bye Mitro.
You...
Good morning Karan. Back so early?
I didn't know you were in town.
Just arrived an hour ago.
It was a long flight.
Everything Ok at college? - Everything's fine Dad.
Have you decided which American university..
..you want to go to next year?
Michigan university, it's a famous university.. then there's..
Carnegie Mellon, Wharton..
I know the list.
Hello.. Karan wait!
I can't hear you clearly call me later. I told you to call later.
I know that you know about the lists.
But life doesn't just happen to you.
You've got to plan it..
Every second someone is born in this country's drainage.
Nobody cares about them. Neither the government nor God.
I don't want.
Do something. Or else you will be one of them.
Please, don't start with your lectures.
SMS generation. Any conversation that goes beyond..
..four lines becomes a lecture.
Hello..
Signal's weak here give me a second. I will just go out and talk.
Yes, tell me. The deal is off then, we are not interested..
You are wasting my time.
You know Russian quality is doubtful..
..they can't afford to be arrogant.
It is a profitable deal.
Anyway in the open market they'd not get half of it.
And you know how many fathers there..
..are to every deal in India.
Nothing.
Tell them we won't bargain, they should wire the money to us.
I did try to warn you.. they won't turn up.
DJ promised me.
Oh! DJ promised you!
So you really are a filmmaker?
Karan.. Why are you so late?
And where are the others?
The Young Guns Of India. Very dramatic.
Where are you going?
Well that's one part cast.
I am sure Karan can tell us where his friends are.
How are you? I am fine. I am preparing omelets.
She's an eight. Yeah! Wow! Nine.
What a girl! Oye Chotu get me a cup of tea..
Two, tell her to go..
Six..
Ten! What? - Ten from far and enough from close,
Dude.. looks at those legs!
Shake it baby, shake it..
Oh shit!
Don't be silly, that's at least an eight.
Thought I'd find you stuffing your faces.
You lazy good for nothings.
We were about to come.. but..
..we are waiting for Karan actually.
Oh! So you were waiting for Karan. - Yes.
Karan was there on time. ..Yeah!
We are waiting for him here and he was waiting for us there.
We were supposed to meet here. - What confusion..
You're Ashfaqulla Khan.
You're Rajguru. - The hero right!
And you know who you are?
The Master of Disguise and Deception.
Chandrashekhar Azad.
I will die on you.
Learn the lines properly, we meet tomorrow.
The practice will be tomorrow at 8 a.m. sharp!
Nine. - Sharp at eight.
That's fine. - We've already wasted a day..
Aslam, your sister-in-law looks even better when she's angry.
I have fallen in love.
What are you doing Laxman?
Party High Command is really happy with your work.
These demonstrations that you have started against Western culture..
..they've helped us overshadow other parties.
Come. Come.
Give me. - Take this.
This is for you. And this is for your boys.
It's not necessary, Mishraji.
I'm not doing this for money.
I really believe in the principles of my party.
That's fine Laxman..
..but every movement needs fuel.. Keep it.
Come, how is your work going on?
March the 14th we started our rehearsals.
To say I was nervous, would be an understatement.
"There is nothing you can do to break me."
"Because I have made pain my friend."
"..As I hold Death's fingers."
DJ idiot, don't spoil my concentration.
Please guys, be serious. - Okay, sorry..
Look, Death's finger.
"I've committed my life to the freedom of this country.
..I know you want me to get married..
..but I have made freedom my bride.."
"Your son, Bhagat Singh."
Who talks like this for God's sake? - Your son.
My bride is freedom.. what's his problem?
I think it's a good line for Sukhi..
Since no girl is ever going to marry him..
Let freedom be his bride.
Laugh bastards, laugh. I won't invite you in my marriage.
You were happy just now and now you turned sad.
"What sign did you make by touching my heart?"
"The climate has changed and I have started liking the environment.."
Wow! Great!
This is the sari round of the Miss Freedom contest.
Just thought it would help me get into the character.
Wow! - Idiots.
Hey, Miss Universe .. ..ity.
Look guys this isn't going to work.
You have to work hard to bring out the characters. And be serious.
Unless you emote from within..
..you won't understand these characters.
Try.. it will come from within you.
See, he's got a hold of his character already.
You understood the character pretty fast.
Please stop it. Just shut up or get out.
See! Now you look like a revolutionary!
Whatever you say Gulabo, you need me to create the mood.
DJ watch it.
Now she's upset! She's is upset..
She is smiling, she will be allured if she smiles.
Those are the words of a 23 year old.
That's how old Bhagat Singh was when he died: 23.
Those were different times Sue.
Today, if you tell people that you ..
..want to give your life for your country..
..they'll call you mad.
Exactly.
I can't relate to this..
That's it. Don't think.
Feel. Just read the words, and you'll get what he was feeling.
Why don't we try again?
Let's try again..
I've committed my life to the freedom of this country. - Good.
..a job.. a well settled life.. these things don't matter anymore.
..I know you want me to get married..
..but I have made freedom my bride..
I the son Mother India.. swear on this..
I the son Mother India.. swear on this pious fire..
This Aslam is a real stud..
Take a look at the packaging. Poetry, good looks, reading hands!
DJ, I'm scared at times that I'll remain a bachelor all my life.
Trust me I won't let you die a bachelor.
Promise.. - It's DJ's promise.
Oh no.
"You'll be writing people's destinies..
.." "You'll be bringing them on right path.."
Papu, change the channel. - "You know the art of changing destiny.."
"You have to go far beyond the lines.." - I like that.
Your love line is very strong..
The man of your dreams will come along in a black T-shirt and say:.
"What sign did you make by touching my heart.."
Do I even have a love line?
You must have washed it off in the loo.
"Defence Minister Shastri has also been implicated
in the MIG-21 kickbacks scandal,"
This is really depressing nonsense. Let's go DJ.
"This is a blatant lie. I am ordering an investigation."
"To the Mahal of the Taj.."
"To the Minar of Kutub.."
"To the Kumari of Kanya.."
"To the beaches of Goa.."
"To the whole of India, Zindabad.."
"All have something to say.."
"They all have something to say.."
"India and Pakistan, Bangladesh all in a song.."
"Kajurao in Coimbatore.."
"Everyone all around say, our school is a school for fun.."
"..everyone all around say, our school is a school for fun.."
"To all the corners of the earth."
"To what is all our worth."
"What is out destiny?"
"From the King of India up to the Himalayas."
"Across the Ganga Jamuna."
"Our school is a school filled with fun."
"Lose control.."
Bye. - Bye.
See you guys.
You're my buddy.. I'll drop you home.
I don't need any help, it's just two lanes away. You just sit calmly.
We are not so drunk.. not to remember your home.
Idiots!
You're very lucky to have friends like them.
One day this will all end.
We'll all go our separate ways.
But you can always keep in touch.
Doesn't happen.
Life gets busy.
Too many problems. Getting a job, a house, money.
And then dance to the tune of life.
In college we rule our destinies..
But after college we have to dance to fate's tune.
You know Gulabo, I passed out 5 years ago..
..but I still hang around..
I don't understand.
..I don't ever want to leave college.
Why?
At least in the campus I'm someone.. people know me.
DJ's somebody..
People expect me to do something big in life.
But when I'm out on the streets..
It's all the beer's fault.. Everything came out.
You know what else I'm scared of?
Acting in your film.
Don't worry.. you're in safe hands.
"My friend is tall but his lane is small."
It's Aslam's lane. - Mind you watch it. I am Muhamad Ali.
Don't be silly. Muhamad Ali. - Don't be silly.
Where have you been?
Hello Uncle..
We'll catch up tomorrow Aslam..
Let's go.
You've been drinking?
Father, you know I don't drink.
Good-for-nothings.. - Whatever, they're my friends.
Friends! They feel no shame standing in front of..
..your father with alcohol on their breath.
Why can't you get friends in your own community?
Why do you make friends with people who..
..corrupt you, disgrace your religion..
This has nothing to do with religion, Father.
Shut up! Don't raise your voice in the presence of your father.
He's right.
This country has never accepted Muslims and it never will..
How can you be so passive!
Do you ever see me mixing with a Hindu? Have you ever seen?
I'm not you and I don't want to be like you brother.
I can't fill myself with so much hate..
Coward that's what you are.
Stop it!
I feel suffocated in this house. It's the same ..
..old thing every single day..
Carnivals will be held on our graves every year,
That's all that will be left of us, when we die for our country.
Well said. - Well said Ashfaq Sahab..
If the English could hear you they would ..
..leave this country in a moment.
So what has been decided?
We'll steal the Empire's money from the train that passes Kakori.
And with that money we will buy arms.
Bismil will explain everything.
Yes Bismil.. Where is my Ram?
Where is my Ram?
I just can't find my Ramprasad Bismil.
Relax. We will find him.
But where? How?
Very soon. Don't you wo..
Oh no.
You won't get Ramprasad Bismil out here.
You need a true Indian.
How can you find Indian revolutionaries amongst..
..people who want to be Westerners?
Ignore him. Let's go.
Ramprasad Bismil wished to be reborn a hundred times..
..so that he could give his life for his country a hundred times over.
Let's go from here Su.
So where do you think I can find my Bismil?
I don't believe this.
'The desire to rebel now fills our hearts'
'We have yet to test the strength of the murderer's might'
'Why does he not say a word?
'The one in my sights has his lips sealed'
'O martyrs, O men of valour, I'd give my life for you'
'In every lane even the enemy sings your praise these days'
'When the time will come, we shall show you, O sky'
'What is the point in speaking now of what lies in our hearts?'
' They drag us all together in hope of execution'
'Those fired by passion are gathered in the murderer's lane'
'We have yet to test the strength of the murderer's might'
The desire to rebel now fills our hearts
' We have yet to test the strength of the murderer's might'
Sue, this isn't London. You don't know what kind..
..of scum, men like Laxman Pandey are.
Look Sue if he is a part of this, then I can't do the film.
If you have any problems with me say it on my face.
Don't stab me in the back like a coward.
Pandey leave! We don't want trouble..
Speak you coward. What were you saying?
Aslam, sit here. Where are you going?
Bastard, what were you saying?
Hey you! How dare you hit Aslam
Don't spare him.
Sukhi! - Stop it please.. Karan, stop him..
Thrash the bastard! Thrash the bastard! Thrash the bastard!
Sonia do something.
Hey hit him.. - Stop it..
Stop it.. Stop it.. Stop it.. Stop it before I say..
Aslam, do something
Stop it.. Stop it.. Stop it.. Stop it before I say.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry, I took you guys in my film.
God knows what made me come here..
I was so stupid to pack my bags and come to a place..
..where people are just looking for an excuse to kill each other.
Well atleast now you all will have one less excuse.
Sue!
Sue! Sue, we are sorry.
You know we've got a problem with Pandey. There's a lot of bad blood.
And if I stay, it's sure to happen again. - No, Sue. I am saying it.
We've worked it out.
You won't have any problems.
Sue.. we all know how much this film means to you.
We want to help you finish what you came here to do.
Everyone wants you to stay.
I want you to stay.
Say something..
I am scared.
Don't worry, you're in safe hands.
Come on.. Get up. ..Come here.
"If a girl smiles it means that she is allured.."
Hey brother she will stay back. She's not going anywhere.
You are a good actor. Now, clean the room.
Now just chill. Look at this.
The next four weeks were the hardest of my entire life.
And the happiest.
God is one. Truth is His name
He is the Creator
The Fearless. Without Enmity.
The Immortal
The Unborn, Self-illuminated
By the grace of the Guru
Recite
True in the beginning
True before Time
True in the present
Guru Nanak will be forever true
Thought cannot create Him
Even though one may try
He cannot be attained through silence
Even though meditation is unbroken
The devout's hunger for God can never be satisfied
Despite the many worldly riches you may have
Use the riches as you will. But none will help you to attain God
How shall a man justify himself?
How can the screen of falsehood be torn?
Nanak, by abiding the will of God as ordained by Him
The Pure belong to God. And Victory is God's alone
"Take some soil of my land.."
"Take some soil of my land, the scent of this air.."
"Add the breath of my being, the throbbing of my heart.."
"And the zeal, that races through my blood.."
"Take all these, and stir it. Then watch as it brings out the colour"
"Watch as it brings out the colour of patriotism, my friend."
"Watch as it brings out the colour." ..
"Watch as it brings out the colour.."
"Watch as it brings out the colour.." ..
Bismil's sent a message..
..that the Lucknow train..
..carrying the Empire's money.. will be looted by us in Kakori..
..while eating Kakori kababs.
And we will buy bombs with that money. What will we buy? Bombs.
Leave her alone.. She will stop giving milk.
"Give colour to your dreams. And those of your people."
"Give colour to your happiness. And your sadness too."
"Give colour to generations.. Give colour to the field.."
"Give colour to the beat of your heart. And that of your music."
"Give colour to every cheek. Give colour to your eyes.."
"Watch as it brings out the colour of patriotism my friend.."
"Watch as it brings out the colour.."
"Take some soil of my land, the scent of this air.."
"Add the breath of my being, the throbbing of my heart."
"And the zeal, that races through my blood.."
"Take all these and stir it. Then watch as it brings out the colour"
"Watch as it brings out the colour of patriotism, my friend.."
"Watch as it brings out the colour.."
Bismil's message and the Train going to Lucknow. Hey Chotu!
Did you get Bismil's message?
No. - No! Then Listen..
The train that is leaving after eight days..
.. we will loot it in Kakori..
It's loaded with the Empire's money.
Will you loot it? - No.
Oye.. we will be buying arms from it.
What will we buy? - Arms..
Yes.. Very Good.. go now.
"On a slow fire, won't you, put this passion to cook.."
"Then as it simmers, add a babbling brook.." - Let's rock!
"Add a river, and an ocean. Maybe a pot of water.."
"Then sprinkle a bit. Stir it all up."
"And watch as it brings out the colour.."
"Watch as it brings out the colour of patriotism, my friend.."
Bismil has sent a message..
..the Lucknow train..
..which carries the Empire's money..
..will be looted by us in seven days, in Kakori..
And we will buy bombs with that money.
"Now paint the whole town with it. Paint your very being."
"Paint your every vein with it. Paint it with a smile.."
"Paint those childhood years, won't you.
Paint the flush of youth.."
"Don't hesitate, my friend. Paint your patriotism over everything.."
"Watch as it brings out the colour of patriotism, my friend.."
"Take some soil of my land.."
"Take some soil of my land, the scent of this air.."
"Add the breath of my being, the throbbing of my heart.."
"And the zeal, that races through my blood.."
"Take all these and stir it. Then watch as it brings out the colour"
"Watch as it brings out the colour of patriotism, my friend."
"Watch as it brings out the colour."
"Watch as it brings out the colour of.."
"Watch as it brings out the colour of patriotism, my friend."
The Kakori robbery on August 9th 1925 that's where it all started.
Nothing would ever be the same after that.
British Officers.. around 20 to 25 of them.
We have to call it off! We've nearly reached Kakori.
Stop Ashfaq, quick.
Ashfaq, stop!
It's too late to back out now.. Come on.. Move!
Get inside!
Keep the windows shut..
..no Indian will be hurt..
Come on!
The keys! - You won't get away with this.
Give me the keys! - I don't have it. I don't have it.
Banwari get the sledge-hammer.
I'll handle them. You go get the money..
Kakori had sent shock waves throughout the establishment.
But we had none to blame but ourselves.
What we were hearing were the echoes of our own guns.
Fire..
Load.
Load
Fire..
Jallianwala Baug meeting essentially nonviolent people..
..considered taking up arms.
This was when Bhagat Singh stepped out of the shadows..
..to claim his destiny.
I've committed my life to the freedom of this country.
Comfort and other worldly desires do not attract me.
I know you want me to get married and settle down..
..like all parents do.
But freedom is my bride.
I hope you'll forgive me. Your most obedient son..
Bhagat Singh.
Cut.
Let's take a break.
Breakfast? No..
Put it there.
General Dyer? How can one even think of doing something like this?
I can't believe that he actually killed more..
.. than 400 people at Jallianwala Baugh.
379.. that was the official figure.
Actually nearly 1000 people were butchered..
Here.
Last year at the tomb of Peer Sai, I prayed for Daljeet's well being.
Who's Daljeet?
We were the epitome of tolerance.
Even an ant reacts. But we are conditioned ..
..to take everything lying down.
Rubbish! It's today's generation
.. which lacks the will to do anything
Have you ever heard of Shaheed Uddham Singh?
He went all the way to London and killed that Dyer.
..because he was also a part of the Jallianwala Baugh massacre.
Eat it Sonia. The butter will strengthen your bones.
In Punjab every mother sends at least one son to the army.
Why should we retreat? Sacrifice runs in our blood.
Only idiots like DJ retreat.
Why does it always come back to me?
Shut up and eat your paratha. Gollu, bring the lassi.
We are taught from our childhood to adjust our self.
Six people sitting on a seat for four..
..someone will squeeze in and say Please adjust!
Hey! Why are you adjusting? Come sit, sit.
Hey, brother, hey, brother.
Strange. Isn't it?
We are being hunted like animals in our own country..
Ashfaq you should cross the border and get to Afghanistan..
We have many Muslim friends there.
You will be safe with them.
After all you're one of their own.
One of their own? - Hmm..
Why am I not one of your own?
Ashfaq.. I never meant..
Ashfaq..
I didn't mean to hurt you.
This is your country as much as it is mine.
You have a right to fight and die for it too..
Forgive me. - Ram, let us not talk of dying..
I pray that we all live to see our children live in a free country.
Ram run!
Run.. Run..
Where are your other friends?
Where's Azad?
Azad was not a man to be found easily.
A master of disguises appeared and vanished at will.
After months of frustration a break through ..
.. came for the British Government.
Banwari Lal, weakest of the revolutionaries in captivity.
The man who had given us the whereabouts of..
..Bismil and Ashfaqulla agreed to be the bait to trap Azad.
Banwari!
Okay! "Just make an eye to eye contact and learn.."
I loved those songs and dances.
That's the reason we make films in this country.. to dance.
Hey, you Hollywood's relative.
"Just make an eye contact.."
So where are we going? - Yes, where are we going?
Hello! Where?
Special day, special place! - Special Day?
It's amazing. - Isn't it?
Ever since I was a kid I used to come here..
..to watch planes take off.. and watch ..
.. them till they don't disappear in the sky.
These guys have gone crazy!
Come on, face it, you'd love to do that really.
What? Take my shirt off and howl at planes.
I won't mind if you do.
Dream on buddy..
Hey, Wild people. - Boys and girls and ..
.. Sukhi who is always after girls..
Why me all the time?
I want to make a special announcement..
Ma'am, I was wondering if you'd like to ..
.. spend the rest of your life with me..
Will you please marry me?
This is a real love.
"Ajay has done it.." "Ajay has done it.."
"Without saying a word, you steal my heart."
"I'll find happiness by your..
..side I can't stay apart."
"My life tastes sweet now..
..since you walked..
.. through that door."
"When your arms wrap around me..
..I know I've found my shore."
"Without saying a word..
..you steal my heart."
"Sweep through the streets of..
..my mind Like a gentle spring."
"Walk through the corridors of my heart..
..fill the caravan of my dreams."
"I sway to the song..
..of your soul."
"Without saying a word..
..you steal my heart."
"I'll find happiness by your side..
..I can't stay apart."
The first thing that hit me about this man was his voice.
I knew then my job was not going to be easy.
I'll come back later.
My prayers won't stop till my country gets its freedom.
I don't think you can wait till then.
My name is James McKinley. I'm here to find out from you..
..where Azad and the other terrorists are hiding.
Not terrorists. Revolutionaries. Call them Revolutionaries.
Breaking a man bit by bit, they said it would get easier by time.
It never did.
The torture went on for sometime but Bismil didn't break.
Also Ashfaq.
Both men had made pain their friend, they didn't break.
Instead they did something that I had never ..
.. seen any prisoner do before.
Death cannot take you Ashfaq..
.. live in people's hearts and minds.
..as the torture tore their bodies apart.
I think it was the poetry that held their souls together..
The torture didn't work so we thought of other ways.
This is the Holy Quran.
Hindus like Bismil will create a country for themselves.
They're just using you.
He's not fighting for Hindu freedom, ..
.. he's fighting for Hindustan's freedom.
But you won't be able to understand this.
You've been a slave so long you've begun to like it.
Tell us where Azad and the other terrorists are..
..You can still save yourself.
19 December.
It's not your fault, Mr. McKinley..
..you're only doing your duty.
How can I stay loyal?
Tell me..
Tell me.
How can this be the will of God?
Things have become harder for me.
I have not been made to kill these people.
Hey, hey guys what's up?
What's wrong? Did someone die?
Sue.. I haven't seen these guys so serious.
What are you doing to my friends?
It's not me.. it's them. They've really begun to get into this.
Hey Laxman, aren't you coming along?
No. Some other time.
Come on. It's my last night in town.
I'm not really hungry.
Watch us eat then. Come on.
Come on.
To two lovebirds.. may they always be happy.
May the insanity and romance never die. Cheers.
I said cheers guys. - Cheers. Cheers.. Cheers..
I'm insane only about two things in my life.
Sonia and flying.
"What is my heart, take also my life.."
You're lucky to feel so passionately about something.
You have your poetry Aslam.
Just like DJ has his singing.
Everyone has passion for something inside ..
.. them, they just have to find this 'thing'.
Just like our revolutionaries..
..their passion for freedom was greater than ..
.. their love for their own lives.
There's nothing in this world worth giving your life for. Nothing!
Correct, except Umrao Jaan.
Just once.. - Repeat.
Easy DJ..
Yes mama.
Come on Karan, there are things worth giving your life for Karan.
Please.
Like what? Look at Bhagat Singh and Azad ..
.. and the rest of those guys.
They gave their lives for this country.
Look what happened. All for nothing.
It's a shit-hole today. Does any one care about them?
I give a shit.
People like Ajay who fight for their country give a shit.
So that people like you can sleep peacefully.
Give life. - Sonia get real.
Sonia's right.
Sue, it's all-fine for a foreigner like you to say all this..
Out here we're fighting for basics..
..food, clothing and shelter.
Out here you try to change things you'll get even more screwed.
Corruption is in our DNA.
There is no future for this country.
She's talking about the past, you're thinking about the future..
One leg in the past and one leg in the future..
..that's why we're pissing on the present..
DJ just shut up. For once in life get serious.
Karan, it's easy to sit on the outside and be a critic..
..blaming others is even easier.
If you have so many problems then why ..
.. don't you go out there and change things?
This is your country too.
Join politics, the police force, government and clean it up.
But you won't! I'll tell you why..
Because that takes hard work. It's easier to crib.
If you have dare then try yourself to change this country.
Nothing's going to change.
You can go to your grave trying.. it won't make any difference.
Correct.. the only difference will be how you go to your grave..
DJ Releax. - I am relaxed.
I'm not drunk. Am I drunk Sue? - No.
See, the director's word is final. Cut it!
Where were we?
On the way to our graves.
Yes, we all will be carried in the same style to our graves.
We'll all be wrapped in white shrouds when we die.
Only Ajay will be wrapped in the national flag. - DJ stop it.
Karan, you can say whatever you want,
Not even the street dogs will bark when we die.
But Ajay will get a 21 gun salute.
Left, Right. Left, Right. Left, Right..
What are you doing? - Attention! - Attention!
1Move forward! - Move forward.
Karan, this is for you.
For me? Thanks dude.
The girls fall for him anyway..
If anyone deserves the jacket, it's me.
Wow! What a dutiful daughter-in-law.
Now you see, she will touch her f fianc's feet.
DJ's right. Touch my feet, madam.
Come on. - Stupid.
See what women in this country have to put up with?
I think DJ's right. You should respect your traditions.
See, even Sue agrees..
.. a woman's place is at her husband's feet.
Honey, you should know it. - I see.
Mother.. Mother..
These two can be such children.
They spend half their time fighting. The other half making up.
Sweetie-pie, can't you stay a while longer?
No, I have to go..
Sweetie - Pie! Sweetie - Pie! - Shut up guys.
"Don't go dear leaving me behind..
..I swear I will cry.. " - Shut up yaar..
I know how Sonia must be feeling right now..
.. my father was also in the army.
I used to think that way too..
when Ajay's father and I first got married an Air-force pilot's wife.
You realize that..
..your husband has pledged his life for the country.
Whether you like it or not you have to accept it.
I'm so happy Ajay's chosen a girl like you..
.. now I can die in peace. - Don't talk nonsense Ma.
You'll have many more years.. and a dozen grandchildren too.
Grandchildren? First you've got to stay home..
.. long enough to make them, dude.
"The bugle sounds, the enemy wakes. The battle is upon us.. "
"And in our hearts, we feel the swell, of..
.. pride and steel and valour.. "
"For we will play the game of blood, if..
.. dark clouds shroud our land.. "
"Because this day, we walk with death..
.. and laugh at its pale spectre.. "
"We will not fear those cruel swords..
.. our courage is far sharper.. "
"For let them know, their cowardly deeds..
.. , just serve to stoke our fires.. "
"Because this day, we walk with death..
.. and laugh at its pale spectre.. "
"We bade farewell, to this day, knowing it could be our last.. "
"We swore to play, with our lives, never waver in our task.. "
"For we are but the last, few guests..
.. served at fate's great banquet.. "
"Because this day, we walk with death..
.. and laugh at its pale spectre.. "
"We cannot quell, the raging storm, the spirit of revolution.. "
"For it now courses in our veins, like lava truly molten.. "
"We will teach them, the twin lessons, of fear and fortitude.. "
"Our goal cannot now hide for long..
.. when courage is our beacon."
"Because this day, we walk with death..
.. and laugh at its pale spectre.. "
The entire country is in the deep state of mourning..
.. because of the demise of Lala Lajpat Rai.
Just before dying he said, "Every blow rendered on me is the..
.. is the nail imbedded in the coffin of the British imperialism.
It was the calm before the storm.
We have to take drastic measures.
What drastic measures?
Kill him.
C'mon..
Bhagat run! Quick!
Hey go away from here. We don't want to kill any Hindustani.
And the days that followed Azad, Bhagat Singh..
and the others went missing.
This was the period when they coined two words..
.. 'Inquilab Zindabad'
Inquilab Zindabad - "Long live the revolution".
Two words that became the slogan for..
.. the Indian freedom movement.
Great idea!
But Bhagat, escaping will be impossible.
Our main mission is to get caught.. not escape.
What?
If we get caught there will be a trial..
.. we'll get a chance to speak.
We'll be heard.
But if they catch us, they'll hang us for certain.
I know.
But it takes a loud noise to open deaf ears.
Long live the revolution!
They were only smoke bombs, intended to..
.. awaken England from her dreams.
And they had more than achieved their task.
"Feel the unrest sweep through the land.. "
"Feel the unrest. Feel the unrest."
"The embers, they are burning.. "
"The tide, it's turning. You can feel the winds of change.. "
"Feel the unrest sweep through the land Feel the unrest.. "
We are prisoners.. political prisoners..
.. we should be allowed books.. writing material..
.. and at least one daily newspaper.
We will not eat till then. The hunger strike will continue.
The fast and the torture went on for 114 days. 114 days!
Never before in the history of any revolution..
.. had anyone lasted so long.
In such inhumane conditions we could crush these young boys..
.. but we could not crush their souls.
"Our words won't falter now, We will speak our mind.. "
"We won't back down now. Our dreams we won't leave behind.. "
"We won't let the storm die. Injustice we will defy.. "
"You can feel it possess you now. Feel it, your soul claim.. "
"Drink this spirit in one long swallow.
Feel it course through your veins.. "
"Let the celebrations begin now. Feel your body sway.. "
"In every breath feel more alive. To keep the storm at bay.. "
"See the unrest in those eyes. See it all around.. "
"See it in the air, my friend. And in those hearts, abound.. "
"We are engulfed in the shadows But we will come out brighter.. "
"Feel the unrest. Feel the unrest.. "
"We are engulfed in the shadows. But we will come out brighter.. "
"Injustice we will defy.. "
Pretty nice huh? Very pretty.
I like these ones, I think I'll buy them.
This is not an animal.
In breaking news today..
.. a MIG-21 fighter plane has just crashed..
.. this is the second such crash in the past six months..
The Defence Ministry has ordered an investigation into the crash.
We have just received news that the pilot..
.. Flight Lieutenant Ajay Rathod has died in the crash.
Flight Lt Rathod apparently did not eject from the burning plane..
Instead he steered it and crashed it in an open field.
Thus saving many lives
Viewers may recall..
.. that until now, 163 MiG-21 of IAF have crashed..
.. and 66 pilots have lost their lives.
"This game of hide and seek has gone on too long..
.. come home now, won't you."
"I've searched high and low."
"These old eyes are weary so, come home now won't you.. "
"Dusk is spreading like the ache in my heart..
.. my vision blurs, come home now won't you."
"I'm in a place you wouldn't believe Ma."
"Endless skies I can soar."
"Just like your fairy tales, it's filled with dreams."
"A sea of hope with no shore."
"My soul flies here, like a kite without fear.
No one to cut my strings, no more."
Flt. Lt. Ajay Rathod stayed in the plane until the very end..
.. and steered the plane clear of Ambala city.
Thereby saving many lives. But Lt. Rathod
.. had to give away his life.
In the last 10 years over 100 MIG-21..
.. aircrafts of the IAF have crashed..
.. in which over 30 pilots have lost their lives.
Defence Minister Shastri, the CAG report..
.. states that old and defective..
.. Russian spare parts were procured by the government.
Isn't this a case of high-level corruption?
Not at all. I've personally clarified..
.. the issue in the parliament.
This is a downright lie.
The youngsters of today are brash and..
.. irresponsible when it comes to flying planes.
No! I don't agree..
Flt. Lt. Ajay Rathod was an ace pilot..
.. who I trained..
He was a gold medalist. The youngest to clear night sorties.
With over 1000 flying hours..
This can't be the record of an irresponsible pilot.
Defence Minister, how many more pilots..
.. will you send to their graves..
.. before you stop the rot in the system?
Will all our boys die the same way?
We are talking about the one..
"If only I could show you this place, Ma."
"Here waterfalls are made of rainbows."
"There are no roses just bouquets of dreams Ma."
"Their scent, no flower can hope for."
"Here sunlight and shadow walk hand in hand."
"Everything seems bright and new."
"But what is heaven, and all its wonders,
.. when Ma, I don't have you."
From now on, the government will make sure that..
.. only experienced pilots are given access to these machines..
.. and not to rash pilots like Ajay Rathod.
What the hell is he talking about!
I welcome any investigation. I have nothing to hide.
This damn MIG investigation shouldn't take us down.
Relax Sir. Public memory is short. Besides, we'll handle things.
Dead pilots, live very long in the news.
But then, they join the forces to sacrifice their lives. Don't they?
The situation is tense at the moment.
There is growing anger and discontent.
Directed largely towards the government..
.. especially the Defence Minister.
We have with us Ajay Rathod's mother..
The government can't wash its hand off the issue like this.
They are answerable to the public.
If the MIG spare parts were of doubtful quality..
.. why were they bought in the first place?
MIG's can be made again.. But our children..
.. cannot be brought back..
It is very clear, the Defence Minister is morally responsible.
He has to resign.
It looks like the veil has been pulled off the Defence scam.
But how much will be revealed?
Mishra, what's happening?
Our Defence minister says that Ajay Rathod was a novice but..
.. he didn't let his plane crash into the town.
When it developed a snag he didn't try to save his life.
He didn't try to save his life.
He steered it clear of Ambala.. saving thousands of civilians.
Yet the Defence Minister calls him rash.
We want to ask a question that how many of the minister's..
.. children's are in army.
I'm not moving.. this is for Ajay.
This could turn ugly Aunty.
Let it.
"Our blood is raging. It's flowing through the streets."..
.. "But it won't go in vain"
"Our eyes are blood shot for a purpose. A cause we will attain."
"It fell from our bodies, embraced the earth."
"Went winding through streets. A river of courage"
"It surged and swept."
"It flowed to make a new beginning" "Our blood raging.. "
"From gaping wounds, and gashes large,"
"It oozed, slowly and steadily."
"While the pointing fingers, got fists in reply,"
"Yet, our blood was raging"
"It flowed not in vain but with a purpose."
"Our eyes are blood shot for a purpose."
"It fell from our bodies, embraced the earth."
"Our blood is ranging. It's flowing through the streets."
"It surged and swept."
"It flowed to make a new beginning"
"Yet, our blood was raging."
Someone get a doctor! Immediately!
Take her to emergency ward. - Yes doctor.
Fast.
Please stay here. I'll take care of patient. Please.
Greetings!
They were beating up innocent people..
Why didn't you stop them?
You protested against the government, our own party..
The protest was not against the party..
.. it was for the truth.
So many pilots have died..
.. young boys who were fighting for our country.. killed..
.. so that someone in the government could make money.
And our party office doesn't do a thing about it.
Come.. Sit down.
Have some tea.
Don't be so emotional.
In politics there's no place for emotions.
We have big plans for you.
You have to go further. - I don't want to go anywhere.
Only dogs salivate when you show them bone Mishraji.
Beat him.. Beat him..
How's Aunty?
They're doing an MRI. We are waiting.
I am sorry, she's slipped into a coma.
Severe skull damage, coupled with the shock of her son's death.
That's an ugly gash. You need attention.
Nothing will happen to mother.
If you need anything, I am there.
Aslam.. How's he?
What have you come for? Haven't you done enough damage?
Uncle, it isn't what you think.
I'm not interested in what you think and what you want to do..
I'm just going to say this once.
Aslam doesn't know what is good or bad for him.
He's an emotional boy, always has been.
He listens to his heart, not his head.
These are bad times, for people like us.
Don't take him down with you.
Go on.. He's inside.
Guddu, go out.
All parts working?
Don't make me laugh, idiot. It hurts
How's aunty?
She's in a coma. - Oh God!
How can this be happening to us?
Some dinner?
No, don't worry Aunty.
We just came to see Aslam.
We've got to get back to the hospital.
Take care.
See you. Take care.
Listen.. I..
I always.. I'm sorry.
Please eat.
Everything's falling apart..
.. and all I can do is stand and watch.
People like us don't count out here.
A hundred more Ajay's can die and nothing will change.
..and nothing will change.
Ajay did everything right, all his life.. yet..
.. he was a good pilot, a good friend, a good son..
.. he never harmed a soul, he never did anything wrong.
.. he didn't deserve this.. Everything is over suddenly.
.. Sonia didn't deserve this..
As I watched DJ sleep that night a funny thought occurred to me..
.. may be DJ wasn't sleeping.
May be none of them were. May be they were all waking up.
Hey Karan.. they've spoilt your jacket.
Long live India!
The bastard got away with it again.
What can we do..
..when the law of the land protects people like the Defence Minister.
We have to take drastic measures.
What drastic measures?
What do you want to do?
Kill him.
What?
Kill the Defence Minister! Have you lost your mind?
We aren't killers Sonia.
But they are.
Have you lost it Karan!
It's not a blood lust..
.. it's a matter of justice.
I'll get the gun.
Don't instigate, Pandey. We can't start killing..
.. people for any small reason.
You think Ajay's death is a small reason? - Karan, Karan.
Ajay's mother is a small reason?
It is not the matter. Understand me.
Lala Lajpat Rai's death has to be avenged.
Scott has to be killed.
But..
I always thought we didn't believe in anything.
So did I. Until now.
You're insane.
We can get him in the morning while he jogs.
Who's we, huh? Who's going to pull the trigger?
I'll do it!
There's less security in the morning.
There's a chance of getting caught.
No matter what we'll have to take this chance.
The Defence Minister was on his morning walk..
.. at 07:58AM with two body guards..
..when two unidentified gunmen opened fire.
He was hit by 3 bullets in his chest, and..
.. was declared dead on reaching hospital.
Government spokesmen believe that this is..
.. an attempt to destablize the govt.
The country has lost a great leader because..
.. of the cowardly act of some terrorists.
He was a true soldier, a true patriot..
.. who sacrificed his life for the country.
His contribution to the country cannot be described in words.
Sukhi!
Meanwhile our sources have discovered..
.. a telephonic conversation..
.. between the Late Defence Minister Shastri..
.. This conversation took place just a few..
.. days before the Defence Minister's murder.
Sir, nothing to worry, the Russians want..
.. us to reduce our commission.
Didn't you tell them it's not a defence deal, first it is our deal.
That's why I was also adamant, this is the deal, if you want..
Let's go.
Come on.
V.K. Shastri was killed by two unidentified persons.
Paaji, where's DJ?
They were just here.
He hasn't come home all night.
Is everything alright? - Yes.
He said he'd be spending the night at DJ's. - Thank you.
Have you seen DJ?
Is everything alright?
I can't find them or Sonia.. I don't know where they are.
Come with me.. Sit, sit.
Don't worry.. nothing will happen to these boys.. - But DJ..
Daljeet has always been a brat..
.. he used to disappear on his bike for days..
He used disappear for the whole night.
He is my only son, if it had been two to four..
.. I would have slept easily.
I'm scared..
Don't be afraid..
God will take care of everything..
God watches over the people we love.
Defence Minister.. the martyr..
.. one of India's favourite sons.. Bastard!
Read it. they're honoring him with the Bharat Ratna.
All our efforts, wasted.
People need to know the truth.
Sure..
We and have to surrender ourselves for it.
What?
Terrific! You want us to walk right..
..in and give ourselves up!
And whom should we surrender to?
The police are mere puppets.
So what should we do? Should we just sit back?
Let them say anything. - No! Let's kill them all!
Right Pandey? Bang! Bang! Bang!
Someone make him shut up!
You always knew that your father was in it.
You knew everything.
No I didn't know, Sukhi.. - Sukhi is dead..
You're lying!
You always wanted to take revenge on your father.
Sukhi, shut up! - I won't shut up.
Who am I to say anything? This Karan is only yours.
Hey Sukhi. - DJ he's used you.. - Shut up Sukhi.
.. he's used all of us, all of us.
Mark my words, he will be safe, his father will bail him out.
But we'll get caught. And I don't want to die DJ.. - Sukhi.
I don't want to die.
We did all this for Ajay.
What will happen now DJ?
You've decided? - Yes.
I need to know the truth.. don't worry.
I'm not worried. Just don't be late.
The night is still young and the show's name is 'Raat Baki Baat Baki'
.. and I am Rahul, let's rock the party.
There's great DJ remixes coming up.
Nowadays new songs don't work old songs are..
Nothing will happen to you Karan.
That's a promise, nothing will happen to you.
Just give me the names of the others.
I have good contacts.
I'll get you the best lawyers, pull all the strings possible.
But I will get you out from it.
You just have to say that you were forced into it..
.. do you understand ?
And then you are out of this country.
Say something. Do you get me?
Say something Damn it, Your father's reputation..
..his life's work is at stake.
Why did you do it? Why did you do it?
Why did you do it, Dad?
I.. What did I do?
These people don't fear death.
Ajay used to say..
..let death come.. anything for the country.
Ajay..
You'll handle it, out of the country.
Ajay was burnt alive.. not for the country.
You killed him!
You made him a joke..
I know you're very disturbed.
What has happened has happened.
Relax! Let me handle things.
I'll find a way out.
Really Dad? Is there a way out?
Of course. There are many ways.
Yes we'll go away from this country tonight.
You don't have to do this..
I want to.
Sukhi, this might end badly.
Without you guys it will end for me anyway..
Idiot. Come.
Ajay passed away. But his death won't go in vain, ma.
What is it about these boys that make them have no fear?
I think some times a person can be pushed so..
.. far that they reach a place beyond fear.
A place where we find a strange peace where you..
.. free yourselves to do the right thing.
And sometimes that's the hardest thing to do.
Welcome back to Raat Baaki Baat Baaki.
This is Rahul, and you've tuned in to your favourite radio show..
.. let's listen to R.D. Burman's romantic music.
Hey Karan! What a surprise! What're you doing here?
We need a favour. - Sure!
I need you to put us on air.
I didn't understand. Put you on air?
Yeah, now! Live.
I want to go on air. Live. Is it some kind of a joke?
That's impossible man.. I'll lose my job.
It's payback time.
Hey! It's your station. Unreal man!
Gun.. He's got a gun!
Karan you go in. I'll handle it.
Keep the show on. Don't mess with us.
Come on.. leave, don't worry, nothing will happen.
Paaji is anyone inside?
Uncle-ji run. Don't stop.
Gun.. Security he's got a gun!
Don't be a wise guy.
Everybody leave! Out! Move!
Don't panic we won't harm anyone.
Move! Move! Move! Nothing will happen.
Move, Nothing will happen to you.
Nothing will happen to you, don't worry, move..
Hurry up, quick! Till downstairs.
The time is 6:05 a.m. My name is Rahul..
.. And you're listening to "The night is still young".
Today I've got a surprise guest for you.
An old friend of mine Karan Singhania who just..
.. dropped in to say something to all of you..
My name is Karan Singhania.. My friends and I..
.. we killed the Defence Minister Shastri..
I repeat we killed the Defence Minister..
Ravi take me to the radio station quickly. Hurry up!
We are not terrorists. We aren't backed by any foreign organisation.
We don't even belong to any political group..
We're just five students from Delhi University.
We killed the Defense Minister because he murdered..
.. our friend Flight Lieutenant Ajay Rathod..
.. and many other Air Force pilots..
We killed him because after he murdered Ajay,
.. he murdered his name..
Ajay's mother who not only sacrificed him..
.. but also her husband..
.. right now, is fighting for her life..
A Defence Minister is supposed to safegaurd a nation. Not sell it.
Who will stop them? Law.
Men like the Defence Minister aren't just..
.. above the law.. they control it.
We killed the Defence Minister because..
.. he was roaming scot-free..
.. even after committing such a big crime.
What we have done is wrong, may be it's a crime.
But we could not see all this. We have come here to surrender.
We have come here to tell everyone..
.. that we must do something.
We all have to do something.
We've just received news that the Defence..
.. Minister's assassins are hiding in the All India Radio building.
Karan Singhania and his friends are still with us.
Listeners can call in on 3291777.
Until then..
It's done.
"Hey, dude!"
"I just realized."
"There's a fire burning within me."
"It's a new dawn."
"I can feel its light."
"Burn so bright, I could, scorch the sun."
"Cause I'm face to face with the light."
"The dream I once lost, I've found."
"It's blooming."
"It's melting."
"Notes arranging."
"Into a whole new melody."
Will they give us good food in jail?
Food? Next he'll want beer.
You guys have become famous.
Calls are pouring in from all over the country.
Come on! They want to talk to you..
Your news has spread everywhere.
Police! - Police!
This is unreal man. How did this happen?
Where did they come from? This will ruin my career..
Quiet! You move, Karan, get him out.
Karan you get on air.. We don't have much time..
They will catch us within Fifteen minutes..
.. you go and say whatever you want.
Take care.
The Delhi police have reached the spot and..
.. are rescuing civilians trapped in the building.
The responsibility of the Minister's murder..
.. has just reached Calcutta.
I am in Bangalore and as you can see all the students..
.. reporting from Mumbai's Churchgate area..
.. reporting from Cotton College, Guwahati.
.. reporting from S. P. College, Srinagar..
.. reporting from Lucknow University..
.. and the reactions are coming very fast.
Hi, my name is Prakash. And I want to congratulate you.
You did the right thing by killing him.
All our ministers should be lined up and shot.
Mr. Prakash, who all will you shoot?
These corrupt ministers are a reflection of our society.
We've chosen them.
If they are corrupt then so are we.
We need to change ourselves to bring about a change.
Hello this is Principal Sharma, Government..
.. Higher Secondary School from Indore..
You have set a bad example by taking..
.. the law into your own hands.
You're right sir. We're sorry.
But give me the name of one politician who..
.. has gone to jail for his crimes.
Who else is on your hit-list?
We have no hit-list.
How do you feel after killing the Defence Minister?
We had no enmity. It's not that we killed him and have cooled down.
We still have the rage within.
If you get caught you'll be hanged. Aren't you afraid?
No.
As you can see the Black Cats have reached the place.
And the boys who have killed the minister are still inside.
Karan, I don't know whether you did right or wrong..
..while we applaud your courage, do you think you will get out alive?
Death doesn't scare us.
No one should remain alive. I don't want any survivor. - Yes sir.
Sukhi
Bullets are being shot in All India Radio.
Ravi, please make him go quickly.
Shit! They're shooting at us DJ! They're shooting at us!
Shut up for a second!
They're mistaking us for terrorists. They think we're armed.
Don't worry, I will handle it, Don't worry.
No.. Kill me.. Kill me..
Sukhi.. No Sukhi! What did you do! What did you do?
Shit DJ! Just when I was getting good with the girls.. - No, Sukhi..
No, Sukhi..
My name is Indra. What's the difference..
.. between you and terrorists?
There's a big difference.. terrorists kill innocents, we didn't..
Aslam..
..close the door. Quick!
We are not terrorists. Why don't they..
It's not a lust for blood.. it's a matter of justice!
Why are bullets being used when it's clear..
.. that these are college students?
This is Shomu Bose from All India Radio for NDTV.
No matter what you do, this country..
.. will never change. It has no future.
No country is perfect. You've got to make it perfect.
Join the police, military, IAS..
Become a part of the political system..
This country will change.. We will change it!
If you believed the Defence Minister..
.. deserved to be punished then..
.. what about the allegations against your father?
Don't worry.. We'll find a way to fix this.
Is there any way out, Dad?
Of course, I am there, I will handle everything.
I'm sorry Dad..
My name is Daljeet Singh.
There are only two ways to live your life.
Tolerate things the way they are.
Or take responsibility to change them.
Karan Singhania killed his father before coming here.
Shit DJ!
You're bleeding badly!
Relax! It got tired of flowing in my veins.
It just wanted to be free.
Aslam.. Laxman.. Sukhi?
All gone.
.. Karan, I think I'm in love..
.. I never told you dude..
.. can't stop thinking about her..
I know.. she's something else.
You two'll make a great couple.
There's just one problem. I don't know if..
.. the kids will be black or white.
Damn Exhibitionist!
Let me go! They're just boys, damn it!
I always believed that there were two kinds of men in this world.
.. who go to their death screaming and men..
Men who go to their death in silence.
And then I met the third kind.
Sending the commandoes is the death of democracy.
Today is a sad day in the history of Indian politics.
We'll turn this small lamp in to a huge fireball.
There will be an awakening and will take a huge toll on corruption.
The truth has to come out in some way and if it has..
.. to come out like this then we are all for it.
We need such awakening if we want every individual to step out.
Are we going to sit and do nothing?
So we have got to take some steps.
They have done it. They have taken the right decision.
That day will come when everything will be beautiful..
.. and there will be no corruption.
The fire that you have ignited in our minds and hearts..
.. it's not going to fizz out very soon.
We will make sure that your dream goes till the end. - We will do it.
Dear Lord, please accept the sacrifice of the children.
I come here with Sonia a lot just like old times.
And sometimes I hear the voices carried by the evening breeze.
Not words just sounds, sounds of laughter.
Come Bhagat Singh..
Father, what are you doing?
I'm sowing mango seeds. If I plant one, it will reap thousands.
"Hey, dude!"
"I just realized."
"There's a fire burning within me."
"It's a new dawn."
"I can feel its light."
"Burn so bright, I could, scorch the sun."
"Cause I'm face to face with the light."
"The dream I once lost, I've found."
"It's blooming."
"It's melting."
"Notes arranging."
"Into a whole new melody."
"Cause I'm face to face with the light."
"The mist has cleared, I can see the sky."
"A new road, a new journey stands before me."
"If only you could stand by my side."
"The mist has cleared, I can see the sky."
"A new road, a new journey stands before me."
"If only you could stand by my side,
"This fire is ready to face any storm."
"The flames burn brighter and stronger."
"Whether I leave my mark."
"Whether I stay the path."
"Today I've tasted the light..
.. Like a torch, I'm burning bright."
"Cause I'm face to face with the light."
"The mist has cleared, I can see the sky."
"A new road, a new journey, stands before me."
"If only you could stand by my side."
"Cause I'm face to face with the light."